so in this lesson
we will go through several challenges
that a many core processor that is a
processor with a very large number of
cores will face
the first challenge is that as we grow
the number of cores
the coherence traffic between this
course goes up and that is because we
have already seen that rights to shared
memory locations result in invalidations
and subsequent misses on those locations
and both invalidations and the resulting
misses
go onto the shared bus and thus add to
this coherent traffic
as we increase the number of cores we
get more writes per second and as a
result
the bus throughput that we need goes up
until it eventually exceeds what we can
do on a bus
unfortunately the bus
allows us to only do one request at a
time in part
that is needed because we rely on the
bus to produce the easy ordering that we
get between writes to maintain coherence
but that means that really the bus
eventually becomes the bottleneck
so what we need
is a scalable
on-chip network that allows the traffic
to grow as the number of course grows
and then we also need to use directory
coherence
so that we don't rely
on the bus
to serialize everything for us